ARKADIUSZ MODZELEWSKI

Aspiring Data Scientist

Check my website: https://arcadiusm.github.io/



PROFILE

As an engineer with statistical knowledge and business skills I combine best know-how required in Data Science. I constantly work on improving my skills, using the Data Science/Machine Learning courses on coursera.org almost daily. My main characteristics are hard-working and ambitious, resulting in studying at two different universities at the same time. During my Master studies at University of Bonn (world top 35 by Economics & Statistics) I gathered statistical perspective for Data Science as well as experience using R and Python in my projects. My main future goals are to finish my Master project in which I will try to detect anomalies in time series data using LSTM network and finding a job in Data Science/ML.

PROJECTS

- Anomaly detection for time series data with Machine Learning the ongoing project at current work and in the same time M.Sc. thesis.

 Anomaly detection Neural Networks Deep Learning Tensorflow Fython Time series
- Random forest for classification problems research project for Econometrics & Statistics speciality at University of Bonn.

 Random forest | AdaBoost | Gradient Boosting | Scikit-learn | Bagging | Boosting | Python |
- Big Data: New Tricks for Econometrics replication of the research paper written by Chief Economist at Google Hal R. Varian plus my addition of other methods not mentioned in the article.
 RStudio, R Jupyter Notebook KNN Classifier Lasso Ridge Regression TravisCl nbviewer Python

WORK EXPERIENCE

Working Student - Data Engineer

meinestadt.de GmbH

- Since October 2019
- ♥ Germany, Cologne
- Writing Master thesis at company: Machine learning for anomaly detection for time series data
- Geographic Information System (GIS) migration from Solr to new DWH in PostgreSQL
- Creation of Logstash parser configurations for insertion data to Elasticsearch (work with ELK Stack).
- Migration of data from MongoDB to new DWH in PostgreSQL.

Junior Business Researcher

Pisacane Information Services GmbH

- Collection, evaluation and analysis of relevant market data from various business sectors.
- Research for leading international strategy consultancies in various industries.

Student Research Assistant

Max Planck Society

March 2019 - July 2019

- **Q** Germany, Bonn
- Student Research Assistant at one of the institutes in the Max Planck Society (Max Planck Institute for Research on Collective Goods). Max Planck Society has a world-leading reputation as a science and technology research organization, with 33 Nobel Prizes awarded to their scientists.
- Programming tasks related to various experiments with a constant cooperation with researchers from MPI.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

 Python - many different projects at work and at University of Bonn

Pandas NumPy Tensorflow
Seaborn Matplotlib Scikit-learn

- R many different projects at work and at Universities
 ggplot2 shiny forecast tseries
- C, C++, Java used only at University

Databases

Oracle | MongoDB

PostgreSQL SQL NoSQL

Machine Learning

Different machine learning methods e.g.:
 Random Forest Logistic Regression
 PCA KNN Linear Regression

Regularization Gradient Boosting

Econometrics & Statistics

- Time Series Econometrics
- Statistics: statistical tests and procedures

Other platforms and tools

 Jira
 Git
 Github
 GitLab

 PyCharm
 LaTeX
 Solr
 Jupyter

Other skills and abilities

- The willingness to constantly acquire knowledge and the ability to learn quickly
- The ability to work in a team and analytical thinking

WORK EXPERIENCE

Interim Statistician

European Border and Coast Guard Agency - Frontex

April 2018 - October 2018

- Poland, Warsaw
- Preparation of statistical summaries, including data collection, processing and analysis.
- Assistance in managing the data systems.

Market Analysis Trainee

Polish Financial Supervision Authority

September 2017 - October 2017

◆ Poland, Warsaw

- Analysis of the effect of introducing a bank tax on the current banking situation in Poland.
- Forecasting the non-performing loans ratio for selected banks.
- Analysis of the fixed-interest loans available on foreign markets.

EDUCATION

PG Diploma in Machine Learning and Deep Learning International Institute of Information Technology Bangalore



Since July 2020

♀ India, Bangalore

- Rigorous cutting-edge curriculum developed in collaboration with IIIT Bangalore and industry leaders in deep learning
- Practical learning with industry-relevant projects and case studies

M.Sc. Economics (Econometrics & Statistics speciality) Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universitaet Bonn

Since October 2018

- 29th in the Academic Ranking of World Universities by subject Economics (Shanghai Ranking 2017)
- Thesis topis: Anomaly detection for time series data with Machine Learning (used language: Python)

B.Sc. Quantitative Methods in Economics and Information **Systems**

SGH Warsaw School of Economics

☞ Grade: 4.5

m October 2015 - July 2018

- Poland, Warsaw
- Speciality: Mathematical Economics
- Thesis topic: Comparative analysis of backtesting of VaR and ES risk estimation methods for the mWIG40, sWIG80 and WIG20 polish stock indexes (used language: R)

B.Eng. Computer Science

Warsaw University of Technology, **Faculty of Electronics and Information Technology**

™ Grade: 4.5

October 2013 - February 2018

- Poland, Warsaw
- Speciality: Information and Decision-Making Systems in Management
- Thesis topic: Scale-city simulation and generation scheme of traffic organisation (used languages/tools: Matlab, R, Shiny)

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Coursera

- Machine Learning (Approx. 56 hours to complete)
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate (Approx. 3 months to complete, 13h/week)
- Advanced Data Science with IBM (Approx. 4 months to complete, 5h/week)
- Deep Learning Specialization (Approx. 4 months to complete, 5h/week)

Stanford Online

 Statistical Learning (Approx. 9 weeks to complete, 3-5h/week)

DataCamp

- Data Analyst with Python Track (Approx. 60 hours to complete)
- Python Programmer Track (Approx. 52 hours to complete)

ACHIEVEMENTS



Study Scholarships for Graduates of All Disciplines 19/20

German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD - Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdienst) scholarship for graduate studies at University of Bonn



Finalist of the Mathematics Contest for High School Students

Winners of the competition become students of the Warsaw University of Technology without the recruitment process

VOLUNTEER WORK

The Forum of Nowoczesna Youth

- International Officer of Młodzi .Nowocześni (April 2018 - April 2019)
- Vice President of Młodzi .Nowocześni (April 2018 - November 2018)
- President of Młodzi .Nowocześni Mazowsze (October 2017 - September 2018)
- Social Media Coordinator (March 2016 - October 2017)

LANGUAGES

English	IELTS B2/C1
German	B2
Polish	Native

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realising the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation). I also consent to processing of my personal data for the purposes of any future recruitment processes